[ Watch on kissFlix.co ]
=Against The Current=
(Adapted from He Yanshan's novel,
Orchid Fragrance Fate)
=Episode 17=
(This drama does not correspond)
(to any real historical dynasty.)
(The systems, culture, attire and other
dynastic elements have been adapted.)
The bed curtains and bedding have all
been replaced with new ones.
We had very little time,
so the preparations may
not be quite complete.
Third Young Lady, if you need anything,
just let me know.
Baogai has gone to prepare
some hot water for you to drink.
It should be brought over shortly.
Someone will also bring hot water
first thing tomorrow morning.
I'm fine.
See to Aunt Lingxiao and Jinlan first.
It's fine. There's enough for everyone.
Lanxiang!
First Madam knows Jinlan
shouldn't be burdened with worry,
yet she put him in charge.
In truth, she's relying on you.
Jinqi also said he trusts you.
Clearly, you're capable and dependable.
You're too kind, Third Young Lady.
I'll naturally do my utmost
to carry out my masters' instructions.
Please sit.
When I went to see Jinqi
at the Hour of Xu,
he asked why
I hadn't brought a maid with me.
I sent Tongcao to follow Lingdang.
Tongcao,
tell Lanxiang
what you saw.
After leaving Zhichun Hall,
Young Lady Du
said something to Lingdang,
and Lingdang left.
I followed Lingdang the whole way.
She was very cautious,
constantly looking around.
But I was born into the Lin household
and have served
Young Lady since I was little.
I know the residence so well that
I could walk it with my eyes closed.
Naturally, she couldn't spot me.
Later,
I followed Lingdang
to Second Young Master's courtyard.
Lingdang didn't go inside either.
She just said something to two maids
who were delivering hot water,
and then left.
I followed Lingdang back to Luxue Lodge.
After I saw them
lock the courtyard gate,
I returned to Yujiao Garden
and reported back to Young Lady.
It does sound like there's
something odd about Lingdang.
Why wouldn't she accompany Young Lady Du
back to her room so late at night?
I thought it was strange, too,
so I couldn't help telling you.
For now, there's nothing clearly wrong.
But...
Lingdang did come
from outside the household, after all.
You can never truly know
what's in someone's heart.
Now that we're living
in the same courtyard,
and First Madam
has put you in charge,
I thought I should tell you,
so you can be on your guard...
and be prepared.
Please don't think I'm meddling.
After all, we should
never seek to harm others,
but we must always guard against them.
Don't worry, Third Young Lady.
I'll be sure to keep an eye on
Lingdang.
I won't keep you from your work, then.
Go on and get back to it.
Lanxiang.
It's dark at night.
Take this.
You're back.
We still have duties tomorrow morning.
Get some sleep.
You and I have taken turns looking
after Yuchan these past two days.
Neither of us
has developed a single rash.
But Xiaolian...
Everyone else at Luxue Lodge is fine.
She's the only one who fell ill.
You were with Second Madam today.
Did Young Lady Du say anything to you?
Young Lady Du chatted with me for a bit.
She remarked on how hard
Young Master had been working,
having to go out
right after taking a bath.
What's wrong?
Tell me exactly
what Young Lady Du said again.
Young Lady Du said Young Master
had been working hard,
having to go out
right after taking a bath.
What did you say?
I've been looking
after Yuchan this whole time.
How would I know
when Young Master went out?
I just smiled and agreed,
saying that Young Master
had indeed been working hard,
and then I left.
A bath...
Lingdang went to Qingyan Hall.
The maids carrying water...
No.
Hot water.
Baogai.
Where do you need hot water?
I don't need any hot water.
I just came to talk to you.
At this hour?
What could be so important?
The day Young Master
returned from the prison,
the same day Yuchan and I
returned from
the Naval Camp outside the city,
did Lingdang come by?
She did.
Are you sure?
I'm sure.
It was only the afternoon that day,
but you and Yuchan
wanted hot water for a bath.
I hurried to have
the junior maids heat some water.
I still remember there
wasn't enough the first time.
So I had another two buckets
of hot water heated for you.
Lingdang came when you were
heating the first batch of water?
I suffer from menstrual cramps.
After Lingdang found out,
she asked Young Lady Du
for some medicine for me.
That day, she came to bring me the pills
just as I was
busy telling the junior maids
to bring hot water to Yuchan and you.
She even waited for a while.
After I finished,
she explained how to take the medicine.
That day, Xiaolian came to see me.
We talked for a while,
and just then, Yuchan said
she didn't have enough hot water,
so I gave her mine.
Early the next morning,
Yuchan developed a red rash.
You came all this way late at night
just to ask about this?
No one can know
that I asked you about this.
(Could the epidemic
be something other than an illness?)
(Young Master,
aren't you going to take a bath?)
(I poured in a whole bucket
of hot water just now)
(to make some splashing sounds.)
(It's a little hot.)
It's me.
Nanke.
I recognized you.
Has First Madam moved here?
First Madam
is still at Rongzhang House.
She said she needs
to look after Fourth Young Lady.
I suspect the epidemic in the residence
isn't an illness,
but someone poisoning people.
You were sneaking around
because you suspect there's
something wrong with the bathwater?
The maids are very careful
with the masters' food.
It's kept covered,
so it's not easy to tamper with.
But the hot water for bathing
isn't watched as closely
when the maids deliver it.
I suspect
someone has
been poisoning the bathwater.
Who do you suspect?
Young Lady Du and Lingdang.
It's only a suspicion.
Perhaps I'm overthinking it.
Let me.
Please take this to Young Master
and ask him to
have an imperial physician
from the Imperial Medical Service
examine it.
All right.
There's one more thing
I'd like to ask your help with.
(Father, Mother, please don't worry.
Your daughter, Lanxiang)
It must be wonderful
to know how to read and write.
If you want to learn,
I'll teach you.
Really?
Can I learn?
My father learned
to read and write from me.
As long as we're determined,
if we learn two
or three characters every day,
we'll know around
a thousand after a year.
That's enough
for everyday reading and writing.
I am.
I'm determined.
Can she be trusted?
First Madam
has developed a red rash, too.
took a bath during the day?
First Madam said she
worked up a sweat while looking after
Fourth Young Lady during the day,
so she had the maids prepare hot water
for a bath.
Du Cuique and Du Zheng came
to pay their respects at the time
and heard her.
What did First Madam say?
Until we have solid evidence,
we must not act rashly.
The Lin family
cannot afford to be accused
of plotting to harm their lifesavers.
(Lin Residence)
These are First Madam's household
authority token and seal.
First Madam said...
(Lin Residence)
Second Madam is kindhearted,
but easily swayed
and quick to believe rumors.
She can't handle important matters.
Jinlan is intelligent,
but he has a heart condition.
Jinqiao may look big and strong,
but he's still a child at heart.
Second Young Madam
comes from humble origins
and is timid by nature.
She can't keep the people and affairs
of the residence in order.
Xiuwan is spoiled, while Xiuru is timid.
There are so many masters
in this residence,
yet not one of them
can manage the household.
I know about the things Lanxiang
has done for Young Master.
She's intelligent and capable.
Desperate times call
for exceptional measures.
I'm entrusting
the inner residence to Lanxiang.
If I fall unconscious with a fever
before Young Master returns,
Lanxiang will take these
and assist Jinlan
in managing the household.
Xiushu's life and mine,
as well as the lives
of everyone in Fengqi Courtyard,
will all be entrusted to Lanxiang.
The letter.
Thank you.
There's something about
Young Lady Du I need to tell you.
What is it?
When I was chatting
with Young Lady Du earlier,
she was about to go to bed.
I saw that she was wearing
an undershirt made of Xinggu gauze.
I've only ever seen this fabric once.
It was when
Young Madam Zhao was staying here.
She had two undershirts like this.
She said they were
woven from banana fibers
and were extremely precious.
But how could Young Lady Du
have such expensive clothing?
It was a gift.
That person also gave her
Yunzi stones worth a fortune
to win Du Cuique's favor.
Well...
Yuchan and Xiaolian
are both at Fengqi Courtyard now.
Is there anything I can do to help?
Yes.
When you serve Second Young Master
and Second Young Madam tomorrow,
quietly ask around.
What are you doing?
What do you want?
Let go of me!
You're a grown man.
Why do you look like you've seen
a ghost when you see me?
Who knew you'd be up
in the middle of the night
and suddenly show up
outside the military camp?
I have some private business
that may get bloody.
I need the brothers' help.
That's why
I had to gather everyone in secret.
The brothers are all ready.
Let's get to it.
Enough talk.
Let's do it.
Good.
That's my brother.
Just like before,
I'm trusting you
to watch my back.
All right.
As long as I'm still breathing,
no one will lay a hand
on you from behind.
Let's go.
We need to leave the city
as soon as the gates open.
Try not to alert anyone.
All right.
I'll change into civilian clothes.
You go on ahead.
I'll catch up with you.
Already taken care of.
I still need a different weapon.
Don't worry.
We've prepared a weapon for you, too.
No one will see through your disguise.
We're going to fight,
not meet a prospective bride.
Why all the fuss?
Let's go.
(Spring Breeze Carries the Seasons)
Is this all we have?
Given the circumstances,
First Madam said
we'll have to make do.
Just make do with this.
Go ahead and eat.
We only have eggs right now.
Here.
You can have this, too.
I don't want it.
I'll just have some porridge.
Then don't eat it plain.
It's too bland.
Have some pickles.
Cuique.
I asked Fufang about it.
Yesterday at the Hour of Xu,
the one who asked for hot water to bathe
was Concubine Zhou.
Keep an eye on things here.
Take special care
of Young Lady Du and Lingdang.
Don't just eat porridge.
Have some pickles.
Second Young Master,
Second Young Madam.
Where is Concubine Zhou?
She wanted to sleep a little longer.
She hasn't left her room.
What's the matter?
Just tell us.
Concubine Zhou
may have developed a red rash.
Mother.
Mother, open the door.
Don't come in.
Stay away from me.
As far away as possible.
Mother.
Mother, come out and talk to me.
I should've stayed
at Qingyan Hall last night.
I shouldn't have come here with you.
Jinlan, are you all right?
Don't get worked up.
Jinlan, don't get worked up.
I'm fine.
Don't make yourself ill.
Don't worry.
Second Young Master.
Please don't get worked up.
I'm in a hurry
to take care of something.
Young Master is already
trying to find a solution.
I promise
everything will be fine.
Lingdang.
Lingdang! How did this happen?
My poor Lingdang.
Lingdang.
Lingdang, hold on.
I can save you.
Lingdang!
Lingdang.
I know medicine.
I can save you.
I promise I'll save you, Lingdang.
Lingdang.
Young Lady...
- Lingdang.
Lingdang.
- Come back.
- Cuique.
Don't be sad.
She's already gone.
You need to leave now.
You'll catch the epidemic.
Please, just get out of here.
Go.
Lingdang.
Lanxiang.
Lingdang's body can't stay here.
Notify Yinchen at once.
The one delivering the food
is still outside.
They already know.
You two,
go lift the curtain.
She has a fever.
How is Fourth Young Lady?
Her fever hasn't broken.
She's still unconscious.
The red rashes all over her body
have festered and ulcerated.
First Madam was already
deeply distressed
seeing Fourth Young Lady like that.
It's only making her feel worse.
What about Xiaolian and Yuchan?
Xiaolian is unconscious, too.
Yuchan is in the worst condition.
The experienced nannies said
she may not make it through the night.
Lingdang.
♪Spring slips
from the branches once more♪
♪Flowers bloom unseen,
as they have before♪
♪All the joys and sorrows come and go♪
♪While loss leaves winter in the heart♪
♪Though all the world may fade, time
rolls on as countless lives rush by♪
♪Night winds wander
through the halls of long ago♪
♪No page could hold
the longing words can never show♪
♪Every joy and sorrow in
this fleeting life fades into the past♪
Yinchen.
♪As new wounds rise♪
♪While whispers of perfume
linger beneath the eaves♪
Take me to Rongzhang House.
♪Let sorrow spill like shadows over all♪
♪Let love fall to pieces,
let old anger burn away♪
♪Let the past die with yesterday♪
♪One last fire, one last cup of wine♪
♪And silver moonlight
to guide me through the night♪
♪Let beginnings fade
as endings come to call♪
♪From this endless dream,
there's no return at all♪
Lingdang.
Don't just stand around.
Don't you all have work to do?
Right.
Get back to your work.
Second Madam.
Clean that room up properly.
Make sure it's spotless.
Yes.
Xiuwan.
Come on. Take a walk with me.
Yinxian.
Go look after Cuique.
Let's go.
What's wrong?
I've never seen her like this.
Lingdang is dead.
This...
She was fine yesterday.
How did she suddenly die?
The epidemic.
Even if it was the epidemic,
it shouldn't have happened this fast.
The others...
Yinchen said
Yuchan may not make it through tonight.
Maybe Young Master will return today.
What if Young Master
doesn't return until tomorrow?
Can Yuchan hold on until tomorrow?
We're only maids.
Other than waiting
and leaving it to fate,
there's nothing we can do.
Who says there's nothing we can do?
There is something we can do.
Yuchan worked so hard
to climb out of hardship.
She still wants to live a good life.
Xiaolian still wants
to become a first-class maid
so her mother won't have to collect
night soil late at night anymore.
Madam Wu may
be shrewd and a little fierce,
but she's fair in
how she handles things.
She never shortchanges the junior maids.
She's still waiting for Jiugao to marry
so she can become a mother-in-law.
None of them has lived long enough.
No one is allowed to die.
We have to save them.
Hua.
The left side
needs to be fumigated, too.
Second Madam has probably
never seen a dead body in her life.
She must be upset and frightened,
so she's keeping her distance.
Fortunately, Young Lady Du
knows medicine.
Once we've finished cleaning the room,
Second Madam
can stay here without worry.
That's right.
Young Lady Du, Madam Han,
have some tea and take a break.
Yes.
Have some tea first
and soothe your throats.
Thank you for your help.
Think nothing of it.
Now that Lingdang is gone,
Young Lady Du,
please don't stand on ceremony.
Treat these maids as your own
and feel free to give them orders.
Ever since I entered the residence,
everyone from First Madam to the nannies
has treated me with great care.
I've never considered
myself an outsider.
That's right.
First Madam likes that about you.
I need to relieve myself.
Me too.
With all that filth,
I can't believe
you've managed to survive.
You may not care if you live,
but I'm not ready to die yet.
Get down!
In a moment,
you watch Young Master's back.
Charge straight ahead.
I'll watch your back.
If you kill an odd number,
they're all yours.
If you kill an even number,
we split them evenly.
Deal.
Here they come.
We're here to ambush
Commander Yuan
of the Xinjiangkou Naval Camp?
Scared?
We have to make a clean job of it.
We can't leave anyone alive.
A brother like you,
I, Lin Jinqi, will stand by for life.
Look at their direction.
Commander Yuan is heading
to Longjiang Shipyard.
Look.
It should rain tonight.
The rain will wash away every trace.
As long as we do a clean job,
none of this
will have anything to do with us.
What...
How did someone beat us to it?
Chief.
Are we taking on both sides,
or just one?
Wait a little longer.
Kill them!
I am an official of the imperial court.
I can say with a clear conscience
that I have not failed
His Majesty's trust
or wronged the people.
Who might you be
to come for my life?
Avenge our fallen brothers!
Kill!
Brothers!
We'll help Commander Yuan
kill the Wo pirates.
Don't let those three over there escape!
- All right!
Brothers, kill the Wo pirates!
- Kill!
Xiushu.
Mother is here.
Don't be afraid.
Bring Xiaolian some more water. Hurry!
Is anyone else over there?
Come help me!
Where's the medicine
for Madam Wu and Yuchan?
Young Master!
Watch out!
=Against the Current=
(Next Episode's Preview)
Xu Lanxiang.
Xu Lanxiang!
Even as a ghost, I'll never let you go!
♪Spring slips from the
branches once more♪
♪Flowers bloom unseen,
as they have before♪
♪All the joys and sorrows come and go♪
♪While loss leaves winter in the heart♪
♪Though all the world may fade♪
♪Time rolls on as
countless lives rush by♪
♪Night winds wander
through the halls of long ago♪
♪No page could hold the
longing words can never show♪
♪Every joy and sorrow
in this fleeting life♪
♪Fades into the past
as new wounds rise♪
♪While whispers of perfume
linger beneath the eaves♪
♪Let the cold wind rage,
let the wild rain fall♪
♪Let sorrow spill like shadows over all♪
♪Let love fall to pieces,
let old anger burn away♪
♪Let the past die with yesterday♪
♪One last fire, one last cup of wine♪
♪And silver moonlight to
guide me through the night♪
♪Let beginnings fade
as endings come to call♪
♪From this endless dream,
there's no return at all♪
♪Let the cold wind rage,
let the wild rain fall♪
♪Let sorrow spill like shadows over all♪
♪Let love fall to pieces,
let old anger burn away♪
♪Let the past die with yesterday♪
♪One last fire, one last cup of wine♪
♪And silver moonlight to
guide me through the night♪
♪Let beginnings fade
as endings come to call♪
♪From this endless dream,
there's no return at all♪